of
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): people who have been affected not just temporarily, but lastingly and enduringly. I was joined by young men like Michael Wellington-Konis and Jordan Massa, Michael Scavetta, David Alexander, veterans of the most recent conflict in Afghanistan.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): and John Hollis and Ed de Torre, Lester Yarmel, Richard Kennedy, Mel Huston, Lucian Miles,
who have fought
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): in previous wars.
As a
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): matter of fact, Micah Welatikonis has recently returned from Walter Reed, where
he had
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): to undergo the latest round of surgery to his arm, which was severely wounded in Afghanistan.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): combat there and that wound led him to receive the Purple Heart. He was there with his wife Camilla and his three
children to
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): talk to me about his fear that he will be denied benefits and compensation, that he is due, he deserves and needs the disability claim that he may apply for. And of course
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Jordan Massa, also a Purple Heart recipient as a result of a wound that he likewise received in combat, he waited for two years to receive approval of his disability claim, only to learn on October 1 that he will very likely have to wait longer because of the VA furloughing so many of its employees.
Amen.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Others who came to this meeting, Mike Chevetta from Wethersfield, a
veteran who
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): served as an Air Force military police unit deployed to Afghanistan,
who needs
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): the GI Bill,
which he
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): credits as reconnecting him to
a civil
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): society after his return, and...
He
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): has applied for a higher disability rating with the Department of Veterans Affairs based on his continued experience of post-traumatic stress. Jake Jamaskowitz in Rocky Hill, who has served not only in the Army and in Operation Endury Freedom, but on his return now in a non-profit organization assisting other veterans.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): 30% of his paycheck comes from the VA's vocational rehabilitation program, and he receives disability payments. These payments, compensation, claims will run out at the end of October, and the delays are present even now. Discouraging and intimidating.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): these brave combat veterans who have endured so much for our nation, the nation that now has shut down these services because of a small fringe of extremist ideologues in one house of this Congress, one branch of this government, that has succeeded in paralyzing the process.
Thank you.